Hello friends, I hope you all are doing
well and in today's video
we are going to talk about if the insurance policy of your La
electric scooter is about to
expire then
how to renew it because the
insurance we get from the
company is for 5 years in
which only 1 year is first party and the
remaining 4 years are third
party and which is of no use, so
we have to renew it every year
if you want to fully secure your vehicle, then
suppose your
insurance is about to expire then 10-15 days in
advance the company will start sending
you a message through WhatsApp
that brother your
insurance is about to expire, you should
renew it, if your vehicle is
also about to complete 1 year or has completed then the insurance of your
vehicle will also have to be renewed,
so in today's video I will
tell you how we renew it and
you will have a lot of confusion as to
which company would be right to take, in what
manner it should be done, from where it should be done  It will be safe. You will have a
lot of questions in your mind, so
today I am going to tell you that you do
not have to keep any confusion in your mind
and you can
renew your vehicle insurance very easily from the comfort of your home. So I am going to
tell you both the options. The
first way is that brother, you must have received a
text message, so you can go through that
or yours will
tell you itself and
also gives you the option that brother, you can take insurance from whichever company you want. So
how to do it,
come, I will attach
a screen recording of my
mobile so that it is easy for you to understand.
I have turned on screen recording
and I have taken out an S Pen from my mobile so that it is
easy to explain. So
here friends, you can see that
I have received a message like this and it is possible that
you may have received it here too. You can see that
this message will be from JM La Electric.
Okay, this is how you must have received this message from here,
you should check it from here because a
lot of fraud is also going on these days, so
you have to confirm whether the
message has come from La Electric or
not. Second, here  It will be written in it, '
Important Your La Scooter' and here
it will be the registration number of your vehicle, friends,
you have to match this also, it should
not be that there is some other number in it,
okay because nowadays friends, a lot of
fraud is going on, so both these things are
confirmed, then below it you will be
written 'Tap to Renew Your Policy', so
when both these things match, that is, your
registration number and where the message came from, only then
you have to click on that link, otherwise you do
not have to do it, okay, so what we will do is
click on this link, friends, as soon as we click on it,
this link will open in front of us, now it will
ask you to renew your scooter
insurance, so here it is written 'Renew Now', so
you have to click here, if
you do it then if you have
already logged in, then you will be directly
logged in like I am logged in, otherwise here
you will have to enter your registered mobile number,
after entering the registered number, you will get
an OTP, then you will
reach here, okay, but I am
already logged in, so I have
come directly here, so  Okay, here in
front of you, now the select insurance
provider is one is ICICI Lombard and the
other is Digit, here it will show you two companies,
you can take whichever of the two you want
and there will be some ups and downs in it,
like ICICI is a little expensive at ₹
1991 and Digit's is ₹11932, now
I will tell you the difference in this and
which one you should take, then you can
decide for yourself, first of all let's talk about
ICICI Lombard, friends, this is what
we have shown, IDV is
11599, now what will be in your mind that brother
what is IDV, it is the
insured declared value, that is,
how much is your vehicle worth in their eyes as of today, okay, that means if there is
any damage to your vehicle or
suppose your vehicle gets stolen or something happens, then they have
insured you for that much amount, that is, they
can give you ₹11599, they will not give more than this,
whereas if you go by Digit, then this is the insured value of your
vehicle  The insurance value that is being charged
is
119 699, so roughly here
you are getting a profit of around 2000 or 00
in the insurance value of our vehicle. The second thing here is that they are insuring
you for ₹1 1971, the
same digit is insuring you for 932, so here there is a
very minor difference, a difference of 3040, so
this is bearable man, but the
insurance value, those digit people are
giving you almost ₹ extra. Now let's see the
benefits, if you come
to ICICI, what all covers will you get,
your accidental damage will be covered, that is, it
covers your bike in case
of damages due to an accident, natural
and mandated and while the bike is being
transported, okay, this will be your cover,
thief and thief, this will be your cover, suppose
something happens to your vehicle, then
see, they have written that the value
will be as per the declared  IDV at the
time of policy purchase, so brother was telling
that the difference of 2000
comes in handy here, the next benefit is natural
disaster, that is, suppose there is a flood,
some typhus comes, okay, hurricanes come,
landslides come and earthquakes come,
in all these if your vehicle gets damaged then
that will be covered, damage due to fire, this is
also a main thing because you must have
heard a lot in LA that brother, brother, there is a fire etc., then that too
if your accidental accident happens, if there is a
fire in it, any problem occurs in your vehicle, then
that will also be covered for you,
secondly it is written in it what is not covered,
that is also a thing to understand when you are
taking insurance that damages while
driving under the influence of alcohol, that is,
if you are driving the vehicle after drinking alcohol
or driving under the influence of any other thing, then if any
damage occurs to your vehicle, then
that cover will not be available, damages to your
bike during war and similar conditions,
you also have to keep this in mind, suppose any  If there is a
war situation or a fight somewhere
and your vehicle gets
damaged in it, then that is not covered for you. The
third thing is the cost of repair replacement
of parts that are damaged due to regular
wear and tear, that is, for example, suppose you have
brick shoes or there is something
in your vehicle which is being used continuously and
it gets damaged, then
you will not get insurance for that. The last thing is any
claim against incident where you are driving without a
valid driving
license, that is, if you do
not have a driving license and your vehicle gets
damaged while driving, then you will
not get any insurance, that is, you must have a
valid driving license. So,
I have shown you these things
in ICICI. Now let's talk about the digit one,
what will you get in it, which is the date zero
description cover, see this is also very
important, it is of 588. Now
what happens in it is get full coverage for the repair
of the scooter parts without any
description charges, that is, this is a very
good thing, zero description cover is
not provided by every company.  But the company that gives it,
everything of yours is covered in it,
okay, if you want more information about it, then
you can
google 2, Digit is giving it for just Rs.89,
okay, I have told you both the things, now let's
see its benefits,
what benefits is Digit Insurance giving us, what is
covered, it is covering exactly the same as
ICICI, natural
disaster, all these things are exactly the same for you, so
now friends, in this you can make your own guess,
which policy is
beneficial for you, now let me tell you, should you take ICICI
or Digit, so
friends, let me tell you one thing,
people have given bad reviews of Digit, but it is
not that Ola is bad, La is running well,
so I will take the Digit one, now how will you take it, suppose
you also want to take
Zero Description cover, then you will have to pay ₹10
more in it, but if your vehicle is
completely covered, then it is a matter of ₹10,
so I will take this, now this is my  The
total is done, my insurance is of ₹10,
so I have taken this one also in it
and in this I will
continue with digit, okay now here it is written
previous policy details, all your
old details will appear here, policy
number, scooter model, expiry date, please
enter expiry date, seven days before and 60
days after current date, now what you have to do,
suppose my policy has
expired on 5th, okay, so now I have to enter today's
date and it can be
7 days before or 60 days after, that is, the
time you have is of 1 month,
so what will I do, like today's date is
12th, so I will put 12 here,
okay because today is 12th, it is late in 7 days, there is no
problem, so the red that was appearing here has gone,
now what you have to do, you have to continue,
as soon as you continue,
your one year on damage is written here
My insured value will be 9699 Your
bike details will come here All your add-ons will
come down here Okay, motor
number is your last six digits,
all your things are already
filled here, this is very beneficial
if you go from there, okay come to
personal details, here if you
want you can edit anything of yours like
name, mobile number, everything can be changed,
now come down, here it is written
previous insurance details, that is, all
your first details will come, now you do
not have to make any more changes in it, okay, everything of yours will come
filled, this is beneficial
because my previous policy which was running was with
this only, with this digit only, so
this time I will not get to change anything in it,
what you have to do next is
process to pay 2389 and GST
is included in it, okay, we will process to pay
from here and you have to pay this, it will
redirect you to the next page,
here you can see the payment request
from  LA Financial Services Private
Limited Okay, expires on 12 November 2024
743 M Okay, now what to do, we will process to
pay here, this will
take us here to the contact details. Now
here friends, many
options will come in front of you for payment option, you
can do it through UPI, you can
do it through card, you can do it through net banking
or you can do it through any wallet. Okay, so
let me do it through UPI. The
payment is done. After the payment is done, you will
also get a message, let's go back
here confirming payment and as soon as
our payment is confirmed here,
we will get a message here, you
can see payment successful LA Financial
Services. In this way our payment
is done. Now we
can download our policy and it will
also be shown on our LA scooter. Okay, we will try it. There is no
problem. Sometimes the page shows that something went wrong,
but
friends, your policy has been done and
after some time you will also get an email here.
Now you  You can see, as I went back, it showed '
Payment in Progress'. This may take a while.
Please stay on the page. Okay,
here you can see checking status, no
claim bonus, validation checking, KYC
status and policy issue. So, after some time,
your policy comes up. There is nothing to
worry about. You will think that
my money might have been deducted and something happens.
Friends, you get your policy
easily. Okay,
come back. See, now your
main page opens comfortably and it is
written here that insurance renewal is in
progress. Processing your insurance
renewal request. You
can see it by going to check status. Here it is written that your payment has been
received. No claim bonus
discount is invalid. Additional payment is
required due to premium increase by
the insurer. There is 1091 more need to be paid.
Okay, now friends, what happens in this? When you
go back and look at your policy here, you will
see one thing here
which surprises me even more.  People had told me and
now I can see here myself that
what happens is that as it is written that no claim
bonus discount is invalid, that is, the
bonus that we sometimes get, which the company
reduces and gives us, sometimes it is not able to give it, so
in this we have to pay some additional
charges, you can see here that
additional payment is required due to
premium increase by the insurer, there is
1091 more need to be paid, so here it is possible
that you may have to pay some more money,
okay, so here we are forced to
pay some more money,
which is very wrong and this should be
told to Ola in advance, okay, many
people had told me this, but I thought that this may
not happen, but it is happening, so there
is live proof in front of you,
that is why I have made this video because it is
possible that you may also face a problem, so
you see, you gave me 00 and
Ola is taking 91 from us even later, so these
things should be told to them in advance, brother, like
discount  What has he written, then
tell us first that you will not get the bonus, then
later on also they are making us make the payment again,
so this thing can also happen to you, so that is why
my purpose was to
tell you that brother you should know, okay let's come
back here and it tries again and comes back,
but no problem, if you go back from
here, as soon as you
go back again and
go to the status, it is written here checking payment
status, then it will take some time, you will
come back here and after some time when
you go again, you can see here that your
policy will be printed, everything is
fine for you, the payment has been done, we have given ₹ 480,
NCB validation is complete,
KYC validation has been successful, we will
come back and when you go here again,
yours is done, see, okay now
you will go here, active policy, right here it
is written comprehensive policy cover, that is,
ours which lasts for 4 years and the second one is
of the bike, you can see this, the sum assured is
13221  And it is written here that it is valid till 13th November 2025.
Now you must have received the message
and you must have also received the payment
email here. Let me show you this,
see your payment is successful, this is your Ola
email for the payment we made later
and after some time our policy will also start
showing here. You can see here, if you
come back,
you can see here, Hi Uma Devi, we
hope you had an email free experience with
us because my scooter is
booked in my madam's name, that is why her name is
coming here and it comes completely here.
You also get the message that
we will issue your policy in a short while
and here you can
also download this policy. You can see here,
this policy of yours can also be downloaded
from here. Let me show you here, okay,
you see in PDF, it will open here
and your policy will appear in front of you here. So
friends, overall it is very
easy. In hardly 510 minutes, you
can renew your policy and your
policy  You can get it on your mobile from here, so
this was the whole funda of
how you can renew the policy of your Ola scooter,
if
you have any question in this, like regarding payment
etc., then
you can go to our comment box and comment
or join our Ola group, if
you have any problem there
which you want to share with others, then you
can do it, there are many of us there who are
always
ready to help you, so friends, I hope
you liked this video, if you liked it, then you can
share it with any of your Ola friends
because if any of your friends has an Ola
scooter and his vehicle is about to complete one year,
then you can share this video with him, so
friends, this is all for today's video,
I will meet you again with some other
great video, till then
thanks.